this whole area 77 business is getting
pretty intense doc and scar have taken
my time machine and hidden it away for
everyone's safety
i can't take on this task alone
i'm gonna need some help and there's
only really one person that i can think
of
that will answer the call against
the man
now all we need
is a way to call him
[Music]
it's pretty quiet out here in hyperspace
man i wonder if there's anything on the
radio kind of need a song to sing to or
something here jumping jiminy that's the
song of the intergalactic hippie horn
man looks like one of our brothers out
there is in trouble we need to crank
this sucker up to 1.21 gigawatts there's
a fellow hippie in need man hang tight
brother rainbow's on the way man
[Music]
hey brother green you called me in
well it looks like we got ourselves a
new ally
in the search for the time machine in
the man himself rendog well actually
it's it's he's called ren bob and he's
totally ren and i don't really know
what's going on but he is a hippie man
himself so i thought we could start like
a little commune here so we got my
little van and ren's van there and
together we can start an anti-government
area that one day
will break in to area 77 but we've got a
long way to go before we can get there
because while we've got two rvs here and
a giant nuclear reactor type thing on
the back of this van
there's still a lot to do we need some
funds we need some infrastructure and
one of the things that i definitely want
to do for this area is actually make it
worthwhile as in i want to make some
farms and i want to make some
laboratories etc for example in my van
which incidentally is not decorated at
all yet down here i really want to make
a little storage room now if i'm going
to be making some flowers and making
some organic farms i really ought to
dress the part don't you think so i'll
change out from my usual skin
and try a little bit of flower power
this is so cute look i got some like
beads on i've got a little flower in my
hair i've got like a headband under
there i wonder what it looks like if i
take my hair off actually yeah i got a
headband i got a headband it's not weird
green eyebrows this is an actual
headband it goes all the way around my
head it's got some flowers on it
absolutely
perfect so i'm ready for this journey i
think have i i've even got some sandals
on this is awesome
okay so now that we've sorted that out
i'm actually going to make this area
here my little storage room but i have
actually got a huge amount of things
that need to be done in this episode and
not all of them are the
hippie area around here so i'm probably
gonna leave a little note for renbob
telling him what he should be uh working
on around here because i've i've got to
go and do uh my mini game which is over
there somewhere and i've actually got to
go and make sahara now this episode
because i've been yeah i've been
slacking on that there we go i've left
him a little bit of an instruction
because i've summoned him using my
amazing woodstock hippie music hippie
horn
and he has arrived but i'm pretty sure
he has no idea why he's actually here so
i've written this out for him hey ren
thanks for joining this commune we are
here because the man doesn't want us
here they are hiding things from us and
hid my time machine if you want to help
we need to build up this area and make
it livable and prepare for the raiding
of the man's house
from gman so yeah we've obviously got
like a nice start here but we need to
build this up so while i'm working on my
other projects i'm really hoping that
ren will pick this up as a little bit of
a project
so let's head over
to my mini game which is the giant
mansion now there's actually quite a lot
to do here if you don't know what this
is yet last episode i started making
this giant mansion and this is basically
the floor is lava now what i'm going to
do is kind of separate this out into
different rooms and each room will have
tokens that you can collect as you run
around the tokens will directly kind of
like an arcade where you can buy toys
and stuff with your tokens
they will convert into prizes so this
nicely separates it all out into three
different rooms now obviously there's
going to be lava on the floor here now
that's the last thing that's going to be
added now i think what i'm going to do
is actually just make the first floor or
the bottom floor here the ground floor
because i think this is going to take a
lot longer than i anticipate now there's
actually going to be quite a lot of
redstone involved in this which is
slightly scaring me i may actually ask
iskal for a little bit of help trying to
get all the dispensers to work properly
but we'll see we'll see if i can manage
then that would be great but knowing me
and knowing my
my redstone prowess i can't see this
going down particularly well i'm making
some pretty good progress here i've
managed to separate it into three rooms
i've added the first floor so you can
definitely see how this is going to pan
out i've even added some things which
you're going to have to parkour to
now one thing about this house is that
you're gonna have to take some risks if
you want some reward one of the big
parts of this game is the fact that
there will be hidden areas for example
you can see that i've built one here
this area might be hidden by a painting
and if you're here you can't see in so
you might jump in and end up jumping
straight in the lava but it's more
likely that a token is going to dispense
over here so it might be worth taking
the risk and as i said in my other
episode i am going to make like a
graveyard section but it's going to go
down into a crypt which i think i'm
going to make around here somewhere so
as you can see this mini game is pretty
big in size and it's going to be kind of
intricate like i'm going to need
lots of different bits of furniture here
and i'm gonna need to make sure that i
make all these different hiding spots
it's gonna be pretty intense i think so
what i'm going to do is actually just
finish off this room so you guys
understand the principles and how this
game is going to work and then i'm
probably going to have to finish a lot
of this off camera because it there's
quite a lot of work that needs to go
into this
so being able to put furniture
everywhere is a big reason why i didn't
add lots of windows if i had loads of
windows all of these little secret
pockets wouldn't be as easy to do
so for example i could put a painting
here
i totally forgot that i still have this
resource pack on
oh man
[Music]
so i could just put some normal
paintings up and like they could go in
there might not always be a gap like for
this one you can kind of see in there
but if i run in and i take the leap i
could just hit the wall flat whoa is it
just invisible there's no back to these
so you can see out of it that's weird
but anyway there might be like a token
here for you to jump down but at the
same time imagine that there was no
signs there at all just hit the wall and
go straight into the lava be a nightmare
so you've sometimes got to take the risk
and just hope that it's an invisible
painting
fake wall
and of course you can just mess up like
i just did hit my head on that and then
you go here collect your token and then
you work out now the more you explore
the mansion of course
the
more you know where all the good spots
are so the more you play the more reward
you get so it will look a lot like this
you press the button boing and then all
of these letters appear and you're like
ah okay so i'm gonna go and collect the
tokens how do i get up there i can't
jump like this maybe i've got to
activate the trap door and then i can
jump up no problem ah is there something
behind here
yes there is i forgot to put lava here
got another token
oh
see now this is an easy level there's
not a lot that you can mess up on here
but it's totally possible so run around
here now is there something here
oh you know i may i messed up i hit my
head
maybe i'll try again okay there is
there's totally a way in here i get i
get the paper and then yada yada
let's take this lava away before i kill
myself in it i don't really want to die
to lava today
so let's take all that back but yeah
that's a really good demonstration of
what this game is going to look like in
the long run
so i'm going to leave this for now and
i'm going to work on this in the
background and i'm definitely going to
leave this resource back on because this
is just hilarious
i totally forgot about this and i gotta
say the whole thing looks the part when
this is all done this is gonna be a very
exciting mini game to play while we're
here we should check the diamond
situation and dig straight down has
anyone been playing yes they have
i don't know if they won or not but
that's not my concern there we go added
some diamonds to the pot and has anyone
been buying some more golden carrots
no
but either way
we need to head over to sahara because i
actually am required to make the
additional extension
to the sahara building
why am i crawling what the heck
what's go
whoa
you guys see this right
what the heck is going on
that was no wait it's still going it's
still happening
it's still
what the heck
i'm flying but i'm not flying oh
i i can't walk
okay
literally
i've asked scar to come and take a look
because
what is going on look i just i can't
if i jump i'm still flying
look scar can he even see me
[Laughter]
help
scar
scar help me
wait does he see what i see
he's just
he doesn't see me flying on scar screen
i'm just standing there
so what does he see when i do this
what does he see cause look at this i'm
bouncing up and down and taking damage
what's going on
this is weird
what kind of witchcraft is this
dude i don't know what's going on
i'm like a dolphin
hey if i use rockets nothing happens
this man needs to be put in area 77.
i'm like i think client-side i'm flying
server-side i'm not
this is i can't actually stop this oh
there we go
fixed
i'm back to adorable
as you were scar as you were
that was really really weird where were
we going
i've totally i've totally been utterly
distracted
i'm pretty sure we were going through
the portal oh we're going we're going
we're going to the old lands we're going
to the old lands
we will be keeping an eye on you flower
hat man
they're going to want to put me in area
every area 77 for that they seem to be
collecting anything weird or minecraft
breaking on the server so any mystery
they're gonna be collecting it
which we might be able to use to our
advantage later down the line
right so we're heading back over to
sahara which apparently is broken a few
more times as amazing as sahara is
it's not really
it's not really delivering as expected
but don't worry this is such an enormous
project and it's so
redstone intensely complicated like no
one has made anything like this in
minecraft before this is a first okay
but because of that because of how
unique it is and how complicated it is
it's a wonderful minecraft project
but at the same time it's it's obviously
gonna have some teething problems but
what we want to do is add a new thing
called sahara now which is a brand new
subscription which will give you
really really good deals and as i can
see here iskal has actually marked out
the area
that he wants me to build in my goodness
this is quite a big extension
hmm and it goes straight in here
well let's plop down all our chests
hopefully i've got enough resources for
something this big
i've got myself loads of white concrete
powder if i run out
we got we got we got enough to be
getting on with so let's start this
little time lapse
on what we're going to do with sahara
house i have no idea what i'm actually
gonna build here i have absolutely no
clue i'm probably just gonna wing this
build i don't have a lot of time so
let's get on with it
now winging a build is not as easy as
you might think it takes quite a lot of
time to plan out something like sahara
so i took a big big gamble by just
throwing myself in there i didn't count
my resources i'd i didn't do anything i
did not plan at all i just had a vague
idea that i was gonna make a tower and i
was just gonna use the same blocks that
sahara has and i quickly realized i
didn't have enough resources
and i had no idea what i was doing so i
kind of went for my fallback when i do
this kind of style which is like this
question mark you can see it's kind of
goes straight at the top down and then
looks like it's gonna go right to the
bottom and then i add some wooden i
basically just went with a bit of a cop
out for this design and then i realized
that it was imbalanced so i tried to do
the same thing on the other side and
actually it came out pretty good i think
i added the words now at the top
obviously because this project is called
sahara now the idea is that you can
cycle through once you've bought a
subscription and check out all of the
shulker box deals so you might end up
with a shulker box full of sand beacons
everything and it might only cost you a
few diamonds at least that's the idea so
this is why i needed to make this
particular build it might look a little
bit unfinished but i've actually
messaged iska and mumbo just to say that
sahara now building is pretty much done
but they might need to
fill in a hole in the roof because
unfortunately i have run out of
resources this took so much and i need
to say a massive massive thank you to
scar i ran out of about all of my
resources halfway through this project
like it did not take long for all of my
resources to be gone i spent thousands
of terra cotta
i've unfortunately i'll admit it in a
bit but when i finish this i'll show you
something but i've spent an awful lot of
resources trying to get this finished
and yeah i really don't want iskall to
know how i went about that but scar came
in and saved me he knows how horrible it
can be to run out of resources on a
project like this especially if you're
time lapsing it so i just want to say a
massive massive thank you to scar who
lent me some resources and i'll be sure
to pay him back but you know what that
looks pretty awesome if you ask me i
really think that that looks cool
it obviously there's a hole in the roof
but other than that
i think it stands out i think it fits in
and i think it complements the build
there as well so hopefully there's more
than enough space for iskall to work
with if there isn't i'm definitely not
remaking that he he he can extend that
further if he needs to but he showed me
the the device i guess that's going to
go in there and it's definitely not
bigger than that so it should be fine
overall i think i've been i am to be
commended on this build it it absolutely
fits in and i haven't built anything on
sahara for quite some time so overall
a plus i think
but unfortunately during the
construction i ran out of terracotta so
badly
oh do you know how this is a whole lot
of terracotta owned by concord do you
know how much this hurts me
that's that's like oh that's like 50
diamonds i had to spend 50 diamonds
to get enough terracotta to build sahara
so
i may have got stunks by trading that
glass back and forth
but at the end they won looks like mumbo
still hasn't got his mustache back
he sure doesn't love turning up to
meetings i actually want to check on how
the
profits are doing for sahara because
i think we've made a few sales at least
quite a few sales more than there were
oh there's white concrete here
i could actually possibly finish the
roof this might just be enough
doesn't look like the pile's gotten any
bigger unfortunately
sahara has not been a financial success
that's for sure but branding is on point
let's finish off this roof right here
because
yeah this is a bit of an eyesore
but at least my part in the sahara now
project
is pretty much complete i make the
buildings then they fill it with all the
contraptions that kind of don't work i'm
kidding they most they mostly work
there's lots of improvements we were
talking about for sahara one of them is
making this ice which we're still
planning on doing to speed up sahara and
you know it
it's it's a work in progress a project
like this is so complicated it really
does take a while to know the best way
to do it and bearing in mind this has
never really been done in minecraft
before
there's definitely probably better ways
of of doing the way the things that
we've done
hey you know what i actually completed
it i after that time lapse i was like no
i'm definitely not gonna manage to pull
this off but nope did it there's no
interior but i'm not gonna be in charge
of that i don't think because i'm pretty
happy with how that stands
oh i didn't mob proof it
that looks you know what this looks like
ladies and gentlemen of the green
channel that looks like an iscal problem
because i'm out
we've got more pressing matters to deal
with over in hermitland
in trying to get back my time machine
but we've done our chores for today and
i'm afraid that really is all i have
time for today i've really really been
working quite hard i've made three
videos in one day because i'm going away
for a while actually i'm on holiday
right now it's actually my birthday
today when recording this obviously it's
uh birthday gone past now
so happy birthday to me for like five
days ago but i just want to say a
massive thank you to everyone for
watching it's been really awesome and a
massive thank you to ren who spent hours
with me before my trip making that
introduction that you saw at the
beginning of the uh at the beginning of
the video if you really like that sort
of thing ren does that all the time in
his videos he has like these little
skits and they're really really fun so
go and check out his channel i will
leave a link in the description
and thank you very much for watching
there's more renbob and green
shenanigans to come
thanks again for watching and good bye
huh
i'm underwater